<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Raster on Tyler Anderson</title>
    <link>/tags/raster/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Raster on Tyler Anderson</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <copyright>&amp;copy; {year} Tyler Anderson</copyright>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate>
    
	    <atom:link href="/tags/raster/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Bison in Montana</title>
      <link>/project/wcs-bison/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Jun 2019 00:00:00 -0400</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/wcs-bison/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-warning&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    Work In Progress&amp;hellip; Page Unfinished
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As part of a class at Clark University, I was part of a consultancy with the &lt;a href=&#34;https://www.wcs.org/our-work/species/bison&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;Wildlife Conservation Society (WCS)&lt;/a&gt; on rangeland trends in Montana and the implications for Bison reintroduction, particularly for partners. Bison are a ecologically important species in the rangeland across the Western US, and remain a vital part of WCS&amp;rsquo;s mission. In particular WCS was interested in who they should partner with across Montana and within the Crown of the Continent ecoregion.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;research-objectives&#34;&gt;Research Objectives&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;em&gt;Where and with whom should WCS build partnerships to successfully reintroduce bison to Montana?&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Where is potential bison habitat in Montana?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the trends in bison habitat vegetation conditions between 2004-2018? Where are these trends occurring?&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;What are the relationships between management unit size and ownership?

&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Federal, state, tribal, private ownerships



  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/wcs-bison/wcs_studyarea.png&#34; &gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Fig 1: Study Area with Rangeland across Montana highlighted&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;habitat-modeling&#34;&gt;Habitat Modeling&lt;/h4&gt;









  
  


&lt;div class=&#34;gallery&#34;&gt;

  
  
  
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-habitat&#34; href=&#34;/project/wcs-bison/habitat/habitat_factors.png&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/project/wcs-bison/habitat/habitat_factors_hu7778a6b46d296ab6032841f7cc980325_21424_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-habitat&#34; href=&#34;/project/wcs-bison/habitat/habitat_factors_vals.png&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/project/wcs-bison/habitat/habitat_factors_vals_hub5d5ce32481f071e1a3e6c87aecc3358_43204_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  
    
    
    
    
    
  &lt;a data-fancybox=&#34;gallery-habitat&#34; href=&#34;/project/wcs-bison/habitat/habitat_final_model.png&#34; &gt;
  &lt;img src=&#34;/project/wcs-bison/habitat/habitat_final_model_hu81215c0062779a29e4324a4e67fb6f85_190705_0x190_resize_lanczos_2.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;
  &lt;/a&gt;
  

  
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&#34;land-ownership&#34;&gt;Land Ownership&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;As ownership&amp;rsquo;s effect on suitable rangeland for bison was such a concern, we used the Montana State Cadastral database to understand how land was allocated in ownership classes across the state. We broke ownership down broadly into 4 groups: private, state, federal, and tribal lands. As seen below in Figure 2, Over half of suitable lands for bison are under private ownership, with federal lands being the next biggest owner.



  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/wcs-bison/montana_ownership.png&#34; &gt;



&lt;figcaption data-pre=&#34;Figure &#34; data-post=&#34;:&#34; &gt;
  &lt;h4&gt;Figure 2: Land Ownership across Bison suitable rangelands in Montana&lt;/h4&gt;
  
&lt;/figcaption&gt;

&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;div class=&#34;alert alert-note&#34;&gt;
  &lt;div&gt;
    More Coming Soon
  &lt;/div&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Massachusetts Forest Cover</title>
      <link>/project/ma-forestcover/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/ma-forestcover/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;For my senior honors thesis, I worked to update a Landsat forest cover map for Massachusetts to 2015. At Clark University forest cover maps for the state have been produced back to the 1970&amp;rsquo;s in ~10 year intervals based on data availability. Landsat 8 data for summer months of 2015 were used, with 15 images (3 per landsat scene) in total. CLASlite was used, a software produced by the Carnegie Institution for Science, which classifies raw imagery into fractional cover (soil, photosyntheic vegatation, and non-photosynthetic vegatation) and forest cover maps. CLASlite is a semi-automated approach, user input is only data and thresholds for classification and masking, and most importantly, it&amp;rsquo;s FREE!



  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/ma-landcover/MA_CLASLITE.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;




  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/ma-landcover/CLASLITE_Methods.png&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

CLASlite has a change detection step included, however we chose to use our own method of doing change detection, as we wanted to use multiple dates of Landsat 8 imagery to classify forest for greater confidence. Each Landsat scene had 3 images, which each were classified into forest cover maps from fractional cover using CLASlite. Confidence of forest was calculated using the equation, $Confidence=\frac{N_{f}-N_{n_f}}{N_{f}+N_{n_f}}$, where $N_{f}$ is the number of times a pixel was classified as forest and $N_{n_f}$ is the number of times a pixel was classified as non-forest. This confidence map was then reclassified to forest cover where values 0 to 0.6 are non-forest, and 0.6 to 1 are forest.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;forest-cover&#34;&gt;Forest Cover&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;


  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/ma-landcover/ForestCover2009_Towns.png&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;




  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/ma-landcover/ForestCover2015_Towns.png&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;




  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/ma-landcover/MA_Validation.png&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

Training Points were generated at 968 locations, stratified by EcoRegion. A basemap from MassGIS with WorldView imagery also from 2015 was used to validate that forest cover was accurately classified. Rate of accuracy varied by EcoRegion, with overall accuracy at 87%.



  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/ma-landcover/ForestLoss_and_Persistance.png&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

Forest and Non-Forest cover persistance, gain, and loss shown. This shows where forest cover has grown and where it has lost area.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&#34;statistics&#34;&gt;Statistics&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;p&gt;


  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/ma-landcover/ForestCoverRateOfLoss.png&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;




  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/ma-landcover/ForestCoverRateOfLoss_StdDev.png&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mexico Land Change</title>
      <link>/project/central-america-landchange/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/central-america-landchange/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;This project created maps of the lands potential to transtion from Forest, Grassland, and Shrubland to Agriculture or Settlement. We used &lt;a href=&#34;http://maps.elie.ucl.ac.be/CCI/viewer/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;ESA CCI Land Cover Data&lt;/a&gt;, reclassified into 7 catagories, and TerrSett&amp;rsquo;s Land Change Modeler tool. This project used 9 explanatory variables, listed in the workflow below, and change analysis to determine the transition potential of each land cover type using the TerrSett MLP model.



  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/central-america-landchange/MX_landcover.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;




  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/central-america-landchange/MX_Methods.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Using change analysis, we can see how catagories are lossing area and gaining area. Forests had the highest net loss out of all catagories, while settlement had the highest net gain. Shrubland had both very high loss and very high gain of area. Grassland had very little transition between 2008 and 2015. The gain loss data is additionally run through a markov chain to determine change allocation.



  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/central-america-landchange/MX_GainLoss.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;


  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/central-america-landchange/MX_Skill.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

The Transition Potential Sub-Models, shown above, were built using MLP. We tested each variable for significance in the model, in order to determine which variables to use in MLP modeling for each of the sub-models. The skill and accuracy of each model is shown, as well as the variables that were used to model transitions. Forest to Agriculture was the hardest sub-model to create, mainly due to the fact that it is the largest transition, and therefore the most difficult. While most of the transition from forest to agriculture is in south-east Mexico, it is also widely spread. Grassland to Agriculture was the transition that had the highest skill score, but is the smallest transition. Transition Potentials for each sub-model are shown below.



  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/central-america-landchange/MX_Transitions.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;overall-transition-potential-and-modeled-2030-land-cover&#34;&gt;Overall Transition Potential and Modeled 2030 Land Cover&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;


  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/central-america-landchange/2030_SoftTransition_2.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

The main area with high transition potential is the Yucatan Penisula, which is concerning due to the fact that it is an area with very high biodiversity and holds vast biosphere reserves for this reason. Meanwhile Northern Mexico has very low transition potential. This map can be used to target areas that may be under threat of conversion in order to create conservation areas.



  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/central-america-landchange/MX_landcover_2030_2.jpg&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>USVI Hurricane Water Quality</title>
      <link>/project/nasa-usvi-hurricane/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 20 Nov 2018 00:00:00 -0500</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/project/nasa-usvi-hurricane/</guid>
      <description>

&lt;p&gt;The US Virgin Islands, located just East of Puerto Rico in the Carribean, consists of three main islands, St. Croix, St. John, and St. Thomas. In 2017, two major hurricanes, Irma and Maria, struck the islands, causing widespread damage. As part of the NASA DEVELOP project, we collabarated with the USVI Coastal Zone Management (CZM) to analyze the image of the hurricanes on water quality around reefs. Tourism is a huge sector in the USVI economy, and reefs are a vital part of that, so knowning the impact of major hurricanes such as Irma and Maria is vital.&lt;/p&gt;




  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/nasa-usvi-hurricane/USVI_TechImage.png&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;Using NASA&amp;rsquo;s Earth Observing Platforms along with ESA&amp;rsquo;s Sentinel-2, we looked at data from Landsat 5, Landsat 8, and Sentinel-2. Landsat 5 was used to look at historical hurricane impacts, while Landsat 8 and Sentinel-2 were used to establish baseline water quality during a non-hurricane year (2016) and post-hurricane water quality. ACOLITE, a standalone program for processing satellite data into ocean color products, was used to batch proccess the data for all 200+ images analyzed in this study.&lt;/p&gt;




  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/nasa-usvi-hurricane/USVI_Sats.png&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;


&lt;p&gt;We analyzed 3 water quality variables, Chlorophyll-a, Suspended Particulate Matter (SPM), and Turbidity. For 2016, we calculated the median value for each pixel, as well the upper quartile. Each 2017 image was per pixel compared to pixel median and upper quartile, in order to create images of areas above 2016 normals. These were used to calculate the percentage of days with data that were calculated as above 2016 normal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&#34;results&#34;&gt;Results&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p&gt;


  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/nasa-usvi-hurricane/USVI_Chla.png&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;




  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/nasa-usvi-hurricane/USVI_SPM.png&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;




  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/nasa-usvi-hurricane/USVI_Turb.png&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;

Residence Time shows the percentage of pixels with data that were flagged as above 2016 normals over time. You can see that over time water quality parameters return to normal, over about 3 months.



  




&lt;figure&gt;

&lt;img src=&#34;/img/projects/nasa-usvi-hurricane/ResidenceTime.png&#34; &gt;


&lt;/figure&gt;
&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
